so i'm
head first into writing this
this anthology a chapter and an
anthology with
a bunch of the people that i've been
talking to and um
specifically what writing about well the
whole anthology is on
d logos
and so the idea is that you know there's
different people that are kind of coming
at it from different angles
and um and so i'm i'm basically
writing about logos and deal logos
and the how how it
essentially essentially how it unfolds
in circling
but as i've been writing it and i've
been thinking about the logos
the logos is like you start thinking
about the logos and it just you just end
up thinking about
literally everything well by everything
anything that
it all has to do with
intelligibility which
if you can talk about it
that by which you can talk about
anything
presupposes that it's intelligible it's
not
you can't even think about it so
and you could say that the logos
as far as i can understand it is
it is that by virtue of which
intelligibility
can gather things as intelligible so in
other words
the meaningful disclosure of the world
its intelligibility is what allows it to
be
disclosed and understandable
so when we start to talk about the
different
uh words or
different names for the logos
it's word it's been translated as
rationality as reason as speech
um as uh
even as christ
so but when you start to speak of those
things right
you're starting to talk about the the
thing that
gathers right
intelligibility itself so if
intelligibility gathers the world
in its in it by virtue of which makes it
intelligent
logos is that which gathers
is the gathering of intelligibility of
itself that then
gathers the world and presents the world
as
intelligible right so it's it's like
it's like the meaning of meeting as
chris would say it's
it's the ratio of the rational it's the
reason of reason it's the
the speaking of speech it's the word of
the word
and so in this sense right
it's it's it's it's the
it's the non-contingent right when you
think about the logos
what we're really talking about is
that which is not contingent right it's
it's a non-contingency and to get that
sense of it like when you really start
to think about that man
it's stunning to what degree we are
swimming within i would say
the the product of the logos
right the the the
we're swimming in things that are
measurable things that are intelligible
we can know about them and be in
response to them
but what what the the
the principle of those of the principle
right
the principle of the principle right
that which is the sustaining source
and the continuing ever generative
non-abiding abiding upon which
gathering upon which that which gathers
right i would say that
that's where we are deaf we don't not
hear the logos anymore
and
you know i think this is what heidegger
i mean the thought that hydrated your
thunk which is just
astounding right seems like almost a
thought that
one should not be able to think right
is
is this sense of the history of being
the being of being right is
has been that by which is the
forgetfulness of being itself
that we're swimming in and
that forgetfulness i'm starting to i
think i'm starting to
understand is it's synonymous with the
deafness
to the logos this is what heraclitus
would say is
you know you listen in a certain sense
you listen to the logos but you do
i'm sorry no it's not that you
you hear the logos but you do not listen
to it
listening right and i think what's
what the could say that in writing of
the logos india logos and seeing
through logos dia through logos
in a certain sense is a way of
enacting a an
attempt to be a attuned to
and be atoned by the logos
however how
to do that to start from where we are i
think is to
begin to hear
that we are not listening
until until you get that you're not
listening until one gets one is not
listening
listening isn't possible but the moment
one understands that they aren't
listening
they can hear that they're not hearing
is the is the same moment that listening
has just begun
and i think that that's essentially what
the logos is in response to and in in
essentially
the the sense of
the sense of what circling as
a phenomena that's spontaneously emerged
in the world and it's spreading
is a revelation of the deafness
and there was in some way a response to
it
so we can tune into listening in the
various
um as john would say the psycho
technologies
the fact of their existence on some
level is the revelation
of this forgetfulness of this deafness
and if we can listen to it we can
maybe hear in those things that the
gathering
of that by virtue of which we can begin
to hear
that we're not listening